



atnicais@gmail.com



646-949-7155



in /in/alexander-nicaise

### **Education**

University at Buffalo (SUNY) Bachelor of Arts, **Communication Design** with Concentration in **Graphic Design** 

August 2012 - May 2017

# **Expertise**

- Front-end Development
- Version Control
- UI/UX Design
- Layout
- Print Product Management
- Photoshop and Photo Retouch

# **Qualities**

Active listener, fast learner, critical and forward thinker, serviceoriented, personable, professional, punctual, organized, and self-driven

Outstanding written and verbal communication skills

# Languages

- English Native Speaker
- · Spanish Partially Conversational

### Overview

Experienced graphic designer and front-end developer. Comfortable in all Adobe Products, along with technologies such as Visual Studio Code, HTML5, CSS (Sass), ReactJS, and TypeScript. Background in layout, art management, web design/development user experience, and design systems.

# **Work Experience**

### Center for Inquiry, Inc. **Art Director**

September 2020 - Present

### Responsibilities:

- Manage, layout, and set up print production for Skeptical Inquirer, Free Inquiry, and Freethought in Action
- · Facilitate and negotiate artwork for magazine covers
- Prepare branding and design elements for each year's CSICon
- · Officiated and created formal branding guide for CFI

### Center for Inquiry, Inc. Front End Designer / Developer

August 2017 - September 2020

#### Responsibilities:

- Overhauled design (UX/UI) of all main websites
- · Built and maintained front-end code base for all websites
- Wrote scripts for any functionality that was necessary
- Migrated some sites to Headless React builds with GatsbyJS
- Assisted users through Wordpress Dashboard

### Axis2Design **Intern Designer**

May 2016 - July 2017

#### Responsibilities:

- Designed stock (posters, business cards, etc.) for clients
- · Provided input and design on any branding projects
- Regulated Wordpress websites through Dashboard
- Cleaned up vector documents

# Certifications

#### **Meta Front-End Developer**

Issued by Coursera Link to Credly Badge available at request